Nikhil Agarwal

 $linked in. com/in/nikhilagarwal-1\\ github. com/enikhu$

SUMMARY

Graduate Computer Science student with 2 years professional experience working on optimization algorithms in the Vehicle Routing Problem domain. Currently research assistant at the Interactive Robotics Lab, working on Reinforcement Learning algorithms, seeking full time position starting June 2021.

EDUCATION

• Arizona State University

Tempe, AZ

Master of Science in Computer Science(Thesis); GPA: (3.83/4.0)

Aug. 2018 - May. 2021

Email: nagarw22@asu.edu

Mobile: 480-868-3692

• PES Institute of Technology

Bangalore, India

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science and Engineering; GPA: (8.53/10.0)

Aug. 2012 - July. 2016

Professional Experience

• Arizona State University

Tempe, AZ

Arizona, US

Research and Teaching Assistant (PyTorch, Bullet, Gym)

Jun 2019 - Present

- Research Assistant Reinforcement Learning: Research on novel reinforcement learning problems, consisting both model-based (PDDM, Dreamer) and model-free (AdaCurv) algorithms applied to MuJoCo-based complex robotic environments.
- Teaching Assistant Artificial Intelligence(CSE 571): The online course on Coursera, offered as part of Masters program at ASU involving 350 students. Created assignments, exams and held TA hours twice a week.

• Intel Labs

Graduate Intern (Tensorflow, PyTorch, Kubernetes)

May 2020 - Aug 2020

• Reinforcement Learning: Worked on developing model-based RL algorithms (PDDM, Dreamer) that learn policies in complex environments faster, while also taking highly risk-averse actions, all by leveraging distributed RL rewards (C-51).

• Tesco PLC Bangalore, India

Software Developer (Java, AWS, React Native, Couchbase)

Aug 2016 - Jun 2018

- Vehicle Routing Problem: Developed Heuristic and meta-heuristic algorithms solving Vehicle Routing Problems in Supply Chain on end-customer delivery schedule optimization for the whole of UK.
 - * Deployed real-time on 350+ stores operating 12500+ delivery vans everyday on multiple shifts.
 - * Increased van utilization by 7-8% across the entire estate.
 - * Awarded resilient individual award for 2017-18 across Tesco Engineering India.
- Tesco Labs: Researched customer shopping behavior when using NLP bots.
 - * Built a IOS/Android hybrid app to test online group shopping behaviour at various age groups using chatbots.
 - $\ast\,$ App went live to a group of 30+ families across UK, receiving positive feedback

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

- Adacurv (PyTorch, Bullet): Worked on 2nd order natural gradient descent based optimization algorithm for model-free Reinforcement Learning, tested on OpenAI gym MuJoCo environments.
- Smart Car (Python, Numpy, VRep): Implemented Max Entropy based Inverse Reinforcement Learning algorithm, training car to avoid random objects using distance sensor in a simulated 3-lane env developed in VRep.
- Quadcopter Play (Tensoflow, VRep): Trained quadcopter to bounce a ball in air, using policy-based RL algorithms VPG and PPO. The environment was built in VRep.
- Image-based Search Engine (Python, Numpy, Pandas): Given an image, used techniques like Page rank, Personalized page rank, k-nearest neighbours, locality sensitive hashing for retrieving similar images from a dataset of 8900+ images belonging to 30 different categories.
- Bitcoin Pricing Prediction (TensorFlow, Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib): Compiled own dataset by crawling web for 33 different parameters. Implemented basic neural network to predict bitcoin prices.

ACTIVITES

- NeurIPS 2019: Finished 12th rank after 2nd round in the Learn to Move Walk Around challenge (Reinforcement Learning on Musculoskeletal Models).
- Phoenix Children's Hospital: Collaborated with doctors from Phoenix Children Hospital as part of Luminosity Lab, ASU on a research project to help identify and address communication gaps between patients and their doctors.